# Miguel Angel Segura Vazquez Software Engineer

55 5964 3832  $\cdot$  miguelseguramx@gmail.com  $\cdot$  @miguelseguramx Rio Balsas 98. Ciudad de Mexico, CP 06500

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience in designing and implementing both frontend and backend projects. I excel in agile environments and proactively tackle challenges to elevate my team's performance. I am seeking a dynamic team that shares my high standards, where I can exploit my passion for Cloud Computing and Infrastructure.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

React.js PostgreSQL AWS Cypress Node.js JavaScript Next.js Three.js Python TypeScript Docker IaC

## LANGUAGES

Spanish - *Native* English - *C1* Portuguese - *B1* 

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Genemod April 2023 - Present

## Software Engineer - United States

- Designed, led, and implemented various software projects.
- Established best practices and development processes, reducing QA bug tickets by 40%.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines using multiple AWS tools.
- Improved a text editor that achieved a 5x increase in speed.
- Optimized a REST API, reducing latency across all endpoints to under 200 milliseconds.

## LeonidasEsteban.com

Sep 2020 - April 2023

## Full Stack Developer - Mexico

- Designed, implemented, and launched 4 distinct products.
- Proposed and implemented new sales strategies, resulting in a 75% increase in revenue.
- Designed, implemented, and optimized a REST API
- Maintained AWS services, achieving a 30% cost reduction.
- Implemented pixel-perfect designs using React.
- Learned and created animations and assets with Blender and Three.js, improving load times from 4 seconds to 300 milliseconds.

## **KIUX**

May 2020 - September 2020

## Frontend Developer - Colombia

- Hired to migrate a simple dashboard from jQuery to React.js, completed one month ahead of the deadline.
- Proposed and implemented new features to enhance the user experience.

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

KodeKloud 2 Courses Completed / Jun 2024

Amazon Skill Builder 2 Courses Completed / Jun 2024

Platzi + 130 Courses Completed / 2019 - Present

UNAM FCPyS - Anthropology / 2019 - 2020

English B1 - C1 CELEX - IPN / 2016 - 2018